<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About Me on Houlton McGuinn</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in About Me on Houlton McGuinn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 22:26:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backyard Hydrogen Line Astronomy</title><link>/posts/hydrogen-line/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 23:19:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/hydrogen-line/</guid><description>We can utilize a cheap (&amp;lt; $250) software-defined radio (SDR) backyard setup to observe the 21cm hydrogen line and probe the structure of our galaxy! One of the best parts of radio astronomy is that you can do it during the day! It can be a little more convenient to observe while the sun is up, and for our case specifically, the Milky Way is overhead for a decent chunk of the day.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>it&amp;rsquo;s nice to meet you :) I&amp;rsquo;m Houlton McGuinn, a software engineer and security researcher. In 2022, I&amp;rsquo;ll be interning at Gusto in San Francisco.
I&amp;rsquo;m studying computer science at UNC Chapel Hill. In my free time, I love indie movies, books, and art! I also enjoy reverse engineering IOT devices.
If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this I&amp;rsquo;d love to chat! Feel free to reach out at houlton.mcguinn@gmail.com.</description></item><item><title>Things I Like</title><link>/interests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/interests/</guid><description>Music The Band CAMINO The Maine Winnetka Bowling League COIN Matt Nathanson Make Out Monday Jukebox The Ghost Maude Latour Shows Scream Normal People Altered Carbon New Girl The Magicians Love Arrested Development Films The Big Sick Byzantium Brooklyn Edge of Seventeen Odd Thomas Haunt God Bless America Night Owls The Big Short Haunter In Your Eyes Keith Goon Stuck in Love Colonia Ex Machina Mr.</description></item></channel></rss>