<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Me on Houlton McGuinn</title>
    <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Me on Houlton McGuinn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 22:26:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hmcguinn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cryptopals Set 3: Block &amp; stream crypto</title>
      <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/posts/cryptopals-set-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 10:15:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hmcguinn.com/posts/cryptopals-set-3/</guid>
      <description>17. The CBC padding oracle This is the best-known attack on modern block-cipher cryptography.
Combine your padding code and your CBC code to write two functions.
The first function should select at random one of the following 10 strings:
MDAwMDAwTm93IHRoYXQgdGhlIHBhcnR5IGlzIGp1bXBpbmc= MDAwMDAxV2l0aCB0aGUgYmFzcyBraWNrZWQgaW4gYW5kIHRoZSBWZWdhJ3MgYXJlIHB1bXBpbic= MDAwMDAyUXVpY2sgdG8gdGhlIHBvaW50LCB0byB0aGUgcG9pbnQsIG5vIGZha2luZw== MDAwMDAzQ29va2luZyBNQydzIGxpa2UgYSBwb3VuZCBvZiBiYWNvbg== MDAwMDA0QnVybmluZyAnZW0sIGlmIHlvdSBhaW4ndCBxdWljayBhbmQgbmltYmxl MDAwMDA1SSBnbyBjcmF6eSB3aGVuIEkgaGVhciBhIGN5bWJhbA== MDAwMDA2QW5kIGEgaGlnaCBoYXQgd2l0aCBhIHNvdXBlZCB1cCB0ZW1wbw== MDAwMDA3SSdtIG9uIGEgcm9sbCwgaXQncyB0aW1lIHRvIGdvIHNvbG8= MDAwMDA4b2xsaW4nIGluIG15IGZpdmUgcG9pbnQgb2g= MDAwMDA5aXRoIG15IHJhZy10b3AgZG93biBzbyBteSBoYWlyIGNhbiBibG93 &amp;hellip; generate a random AES key (which it should save for all future encryptions), pad the string out to the 16-byte AES block size and CBC-encrypt it under that key, providing the caller the ciphertext and IV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptopals Set 2: Block crypto</title>
      <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/posts/cryptopals-set-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hmcguinn.com/posts/cryptopals-set-2/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with Cryptopals, the second set focuses on block ciphers. These were a lot of fun! Trickier than the second set but also more useful and fun to work on!
9. Implement PKCS#7 Padding A block cipher transforms a fixed-sized block (usually 8 or 16 bytes) of plaintext into ciphertext. But we almost never want to transform a single block; we encrypt irregularly-sized messages.
One way we account for irregularly-sized messages is by padding, creating a plaintext that is an even multiple of the blocksize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptopals Set 1: Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/posts/cryptopals-set-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 13:12:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hmcguinn.com/posts/cryptopals-set-1/</guid>
      <description>Cryptopals is a set of cryptography challenges by the NCC Group. Maciej Ceglowski wrote a great blog about them here. They&amp;rsquo;ve been out for a while and I originally tried to work through them four years ago in high school. I got to about the second challenge and then was stumped. Now, four years and a CS degree later, I&amp;rsquo;m back at it! They&amp;rsquo;ve been a ton of fun to work on so far and definitely challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity Lights</title>
      <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/art/gravity_lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 21:26:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hmcguinn.com/art/gravity_lights/</guid>
      <description>This one I think is really cool. Based off of Wandering Stars by Brian Fearn
Modify it here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colorful Shapes</title>
      <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/art/colorful_shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 19:26:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hmcguinn.com/art/colorful_shapes/</guid>
      <description>This was the first piece of generative art I&amp;rsquo;ve made!
Modify it here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Backyard Hydrogen Line Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/posts/hydrogen-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 23:19:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hmcguinn.com/posts/hydrogen-line/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in astronomy and space since I was a kid, but never really did much with it. During my internship at Georgia Tech Research Institute, I learned to use a software-defined radio to investigate vulnerabilities in an IOT camera&amp;rsquo;s over-the-air communication protocol. Reading this post on using an SDR to detect pulsars inspired me. What else could you detect with one? Being interested in both astronomy and SDRs, this project naturally followed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hmcguinn.com/about/</guid>
      <description>it&amp;rsquo;s nice to meet you :) I&amp;rsquo;m Houlton McGuinn, a software engineer and security researcher. In 2023, I&amp;rsquo;ll be starting my full-time career at Retool as a Security Engineer in San Francisco!
I graduated from UNC Chapel Hill last December! In my free time, I love indie movies, books, and art! I also enjoy reverse engineering IoT devices.
If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this I&amp;rsquo;d love to chat! Feel free to reach out at houlton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Like</title>
      <link>https://www.hmcguinn.com/interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hmcguinn.com/interests/</guid>
      <description>Music The Band CAMINO The Maine Winnetka Bowling League COIN Matt Nathanson Make Out Monday Jukebox The Ghost Maude Latour The Wrecks Shows Scream Normal People Altered Carbon New Girl The Magicians Love Arrested Development Films The Big Sick Byzantium Brooklyn Edge of Seventeen Odd Thomas Haunt God Bless America Night Owls The Big Short Haunter In Your Eyes Keith Goon Stuck in Love Colonia Ex Machina Mr. Right What If Hot Fuzz Nightcrawler Heathers Midsommar Moonrise Kingdom Wildflower Sleeping with Other People Adult World Better Living through Chemistry Lord of the Rings The Spectacular Now Tucker and Dale vs Evil White Bird in a Blizzard Cloud Atlas Hot Summer Nights Never goin&amp;rsquo; Back Thoroughbreds Lady Bird Eighth Grade Love, Rosie Nick &amp;amp; Norah&amp;rsquo;s Infinite Playlist Scott Pilgrim vs The World Once Upon a Time in Hollywood Everything Everywhere All at Once </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
